ebuzzing.co.uk 2018-06-29

# Privacy Policy - Teads

## About Teads Service

Teads is an advertising marketplace that proposes innovative advertising solutions to Publishers and Advertisers all over Europe, USA, Latin America and Asia.

Publishers use Teads advertising solutions to monetize their ad spaces either directly or through Teads advertising demand including other advertising buyer partners.

Advertisers or their intermediaries (eg. media agencies) display their advertising campaigns through Teads advertising solutions on the websites or apps of our publishers partners.

Teads advertising technology collects and uses data to help make online advertising more relevant as well as for ad delivery and reporting purposes.

## Scope of this privacy policy

Teads SA., together with its affiliates (“Teads”, “we”, “us”, or “our”) recognizes the importance of privacy and is committed to providing transparency and control over the use of the data in online advertising.

This privacy policy details Teads data practices on how we collect, use, process and share the data we may collect through our advertising services as well as the ways in which individuals may exercise control over the use of information collected by us.

## 1\. User identification

Teads does not collect or process any information that allows identifying a particular individual directly.

We do not collect or process information related to (i) name, user address, place of work, date of birth, email address, or phone number (ii) hardware-based identifiers such as UDID or MAC Address and (iii) sensitive information (such as religion, political opinion, health…).

We do not create segments to specifically target children under 16 years old.

In order to deliver personalized ads as well as non-personalized ads, Teads uses 3 methods to single out users depending on the device they use, web or mobile and operating system :

### Cookie-based identification

Teads drops a cookie on the user web and/or mobile browser. Cookies are used to single out a user and store a randomly generated identifier to identify his browser across visits.

### Cookie-less environments

For some environments – for example, Apple devices using Safari browser – Teads uses an identification methodology based on IP address non-reversible encryption, browser used and operating system. This method allows to single out a user in order to cap the number of times the same ad is shown to the same user.

### Advertising ID

Teads uses its SDK technology for mobile applications. For Google Android operating system, we use the [Google Advertising ID](https://support.google.com/googleplay/android-developer/answer/6048248) and for [Apple iOS the IDFA](https://developer.apple.com/library/content/documentation/LanguagesUtilities/Conceptual/iTunesConnect_Guide/Chapters/SubmittingTheApp.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40011225-CH33-SW8).

## 2\. Information we collect

We collect data through our web tags on publisher web pages, or through our Software Development Kit within publisher mobile Apps.

Collected data are :

  *  **Page URL**
  *  **Browser Information** (eg: Browser name and version)
  *  **Device Information** (eg: Device type, OS)
  *  **Network carrier information** (eg: Wifi, 4G or Wired connection)
  *  **Non-precise Location information** (eg: Country and City, derived from user IP)
  *  **Mobile application information** (eg: Application name or IDFA)
  *  **User Interactions with Teads Ad** (eg: clicks or video views)
  *  **IP address**

To improve advertising relevance for users, Teads uses other data coming from trusted providers in order to infer general users interests (eg. socio-demographic, brand affinity).

## 3\. Data use

We use the information we collect to deliver our services:

  *  **Targeting:** We use data to filter the ad delivery according to user interests, user location, device used or page content.
  *  **User frequency Capping:** We use data to prevent displaying too many times the same ad to the same user.
  *  **Analytics:** We use collected data for monitoring and reporting the campaign delivery for advertisers and publishers and for internal business analysis.
  *  **Ad Delivery:** We transmit collected data to to programmatic buyers so that they can deliver their campaigns.
  *  **Delivery Algorithm training:** We use collected data in order to improve our service and technology.
  *  **Cross device experience:** To provide a consolidated experience through the different device or browser environments, we may link the Teads identifiers on the different browsers and environments the user is using.

## 4\. Data sent to Teads partners

In order to be able to deliver an ad and measure its performance, we need to share data with our different partners. These companies are authorized to use the information we provide only as necessary to provide these services.

  *  **Viewability measurement.** We transmit data to companies specialized in campaign measurement such as MOAT or IAS in order to verify that our ads are viewable.
  *  **Fraud detection.** We transmit data to companies such as DoubleVerify in order to prevent delivering our ads on fraudulent traffic, such as non-human traffic.
  *  **Brand Safety.** We transmit data to companies such as Grapeshot in order to prevent displaying our Ads on content that can damage an advertiser’s Brand.
  *  **Analytics and Audience measurement.** We transmit data to companies such as Nielsen, ComScore or Mediametrie in order to measure the demographics of our audience.

We do also send data to **Programmatic Buyers** using Demand Side Platforms such as Google DoubleClick Bid Manager, who buy our ad placements through programmatic auctions.

## 5\. Data retention and storage

We retain the data linked to a user up to 12 months from the date of collection.

We may also store aggregated and non-personal data for a longer period than 12 months for financial and statistical reasons.

For security reasons, user’ IP address is stored in a private security log for a period of 4 months.

Teads uses generally accepted industry security standards to protect data.

## 6\. Opt-out from Teads personalized Advertising

If you do not want us to show you personalized ads (based on your inferred interests) please follow the below instructions.

### To opt-out from your web browser

If you opt-out, you will still see ads, including contextually tailored ads (i.e., ads tailored to the current website or app you are viewing) and ads based on your current location, they just may not be relevant to your interests.

The opt-out mechanism will only opt you out of personalized advertising delivered by Teads in this browser or in mobile applications on this device (e.g., phones, tablets). It will not opt you out on other devices or in other browsers you use.

If cookies are cleared or deleted in your browser, this may delete the Teads opt-out cookie, and you may need to renew your opt-out choice for that browser.

[You can opt-out from Teads personalized advertising by clicking here](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices)

### To opt-out from your mobile phone

If you opt-out, you will still see ads, including contextually tailored ads (i.e., ads tailored to the current website or app you are viewing) and ads based on your current location, they just may not be relevant to your interests.

If you want to disable Teads personalized ad, please refer to your operating system settings.

Mobile device system softwares are providing mechanisms that allow users to opt-out of the use of information about their usage of mobile apps to deliver targeted ads to their mobile device. For more information, or to opt-out using these mechanisms, consult your device settings (eg. “Opt-out of Interest-Based Ads” on Android devices and “Limit Ad Tracking” on iOS devices).

Please note that this is a device setting which will disable personalized ads from all providers, and not just for Teads.

If your device’s advertising identifier is reset, you will need to renew your opt-out choice for that device.

## 7\. Miscellaneous

### Legal notification

Teads may be required to disclose data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

We may also disclose your information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or other legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request. If Teads is involved in a merger, acquisition, dissolution or sale of all or a portion of its assets, Teads reserves the right to disclose or transfer your data, and you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership, uses of your personal information, and choices you may have regarding your personal data.

### Changes to our privacy policy

Please note that we may update or change this privacy policy. If we revise our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, and to other places we deem appropriate, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any we disclose it. If we make any material changes we will notify you by means of a notice on this site prior to the change becoming effective.

### Contact Us

Upon request, Teads will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access or request deletion of your personal information by contacting us as described below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

For any questions about this Privacy Policy or our data practices, you can contact Teads:

– By email: dpo@teads.tv.  
– By mail: Legal Department (DPO) -Teads – 97 rue du Cherche midi – 75006 Paris – France

Last updated: May 8th 2018
